JACKY LI

📍 San Jose, CA | 🕜 (510) 918-2567 | 🖂 jackyxli+dev@outlook.com | 🛅 LinkedIn | 🖸 GitHub | Portfolio



SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a software engineer with over 3 years of experience where I've demonstrated an ability to adapt and succeed in a wide range of roles and domains. These include, frontend, backend, full-stack, growth engineer, onboarding team, invoicing team, and AI developer. Led high visibility projects at an enterprise level company that have improved business efficiency and lead conversions. Capable of not only deep diving into complex problems, but also deriving solutions, and then communicating it all to technical and non-technical audiences.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Ruby on Rails | React | Javascript | SQL | PostgreSQL | GraphQL Contentful | Gatsby | Netlify | Python | Streamlit AB Testing | Data Science | Prompt Engineering | Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FLEXPORT | Software Engineer, Growth Engineer | Apr 2021 – Oct 2023

Onboarding Checklist Project | Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, React | Jan 2023 - Mar 2023

- Led 6 team members and derived the technical design for a project targeting an external client application to sync the completion status of user onboarding tasks to an internal checklist.
- Iterated on existing data models to support improved flow by writing Ruby on Rails migrations to add new data and to backfill data, and creating new GraphOL queries and resolvers.
- Increased client clearing speeds by 30%, allowing for expedited client onboarding.
- Reduced shipment exceptions by 40% by improving the internal user workflow to reduce manual task completion; thus, saving ~15 hours a week in manual work and improving worker productivity.

Unified Invoicing Experience for A New SMB Application | Ruby on Rails, SQL, Looker | Aug 2023 - Sep 2023

- Acted as main engineering on Flexport side as part of efforts to streamline payments for both Flexport freight and Deliverr fulfillment invoices within Deliverr's ChargeBee system as part of product launch for SMBs.
- Ideated a solution to automate invoice CSV creation by consolidating data from multiple sources to enhance processing speeds, and using Looker to provide a dynamic and easy to use interface for non-technical users.
- With 750 clients and 300 invoices in the quarter the app launched , the automation resulted in time savings equivalent to 13 hours per week of manual effort, not accounting for the time spent rectifying human errors.
- Cross-collaborated with multiple teams, including Finance, Legal, Accounting, and Invoicing to understand their existing processes, data they store and access, and was able to review and get sign off on my approach.

Accelerated Payment Verification Project | Ruby on Rails, React, Amplitude, Sumologic | Sep 2022

- Designed and implemented a quick-release solution to solve the issue of unverified payment methods blocking custom bond purchases by automating reminders for clients to verify their payment methods.
- Leveraged Ruby on Rails jobs and mailers to automatically identify and notify clients with outstanding unverified payment methods.
- Reduced average client time to verify payment from 2 weeks to 4 days and decreased the percentage of blocked customs bond purchases due to unverified payment methods by 25%.
- Resulted in 1/3rd of clients with verified payment methods had an ingress point from reminder emails.

Public Site Refresh | Contentful, React, HTML, CSS, Amplitude, Gatsby, Netlify | Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

- Created a new multi-layered navigation bar and animation for the homepage hero without external libraries.
- Provided the marketing team a no-code solution to dynamically create forms using Contentful.
- Contributed to the development of an in-house AB testing solution to allow the marketing team to dynamically AB test new components and pages by leveraging Contentful modules and Amplitude events.
- The AB testing solution saved the company \$36000 per year, and 2 hours per week of engineering time.
- The revamped website boosted conversion rates by 5% and average visit duration by 50%.

LONELY OCTOPUS | Al Developer | Mar 2024 – May 2024

Streamlit App with AIConfig | Python, Streamlit, AIConfig, ChromaDB | Apr 2024 - May 2024

- Used AIConfig to integrate multiple LLM models and to keep AI behavior separate from application logic.
- Integrated RAG to improve AI responses and reduce hallucinations by ingesting data from supporting documents into a ChromaDB vector database.
- Proposed and presented project to Lastmile AI team, providing documentation, feedback, findings, and more.

EDUCATION & TRAINING